import 'package:nasa/quiz/questions.dart';

final List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the first confirmed exoplanet?',
    options: [
      '51 Pegasi b',
      'Kepler-186f',
      'Proxima Centauri b',
      'HD 209458 b'
    ],
    correctAnswer: '51 Pegasi b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which method is primarily used to discover exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Transit Method',
      'Radial Velocity',
      'Direct Imaging',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "habitability" refer to?',
    options: [
      'Possibility of life',
      'Presence of water',
      'Earth-like conditions',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which of the following is the largest known exoplanet?',
    options: ['HD 100546 b', 'WASP-17b', 'TrES-4', 'Kepler-39b'],
    correctAnswer: 'WASP-17b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the primary component of a gas giant like Jupiter?',
    options: ['Rock', 'Ice', 'Hydrogen and Helium', 'Silicon'],
    correctAnswer: 'Hydrogen and Helium',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which exoplanet is known for having the highest temperature?',
    options: ['KELT-9b', 'HD 189733 b', 'WASP-121 b', 'WASP-103 b'],
    correctAnswer: 'KELT-9b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the "Goldilocks Zone" refer to?',
    options: [
      'A region with gold asteroids',
      'The habitable zone around a star',
      'A star with gold characteristics',
      'A zone with gold planets'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The habitable zone around a star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is a super-Earth?',
    options: [
      'An Earth-like planet',
      'A planet larger than Earth but smaller than Neptune',
      'A planet similar to Jupiter',
      'An exoplanet with life'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A planet larger than Earth but smaller than Neptune',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which mission has been instrumental in discovering exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Hubble Space Telescope',
      'Kepler Space Telescope',
      'Chandra X-ray Observatory',
      'James Webb Space Telescope'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Kepler Space Telescope',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which of the following is NOT a method of detecting exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Transit Method',
      'Astrometry',
      'Radial Velocity',
      'Nuclear Fusion'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Nuclear Fusion',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the closest known exoplanet to Earth?',
    options: [
      'Proxima Centauri b',
      'Barnard\'s Star b',
      'Ross 128 b',
      'Wolf 1061 c'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Proxima Centauri b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is an exoplanet?',
    options: [
      'A planet in our solar system',
      'A planet orbiting a star outside our solar system',
      'A moon of a planet',
      'A dwarf planet'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A planet orbiting a star outside our solar system',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which exoplanet has the shortest orbital period?',
    options: ['WASP-121b', 'WASP-43b', 'HD 189733b', 'HD 3167b'],
    correctAnswer: 'WASP-121b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the significance of the Kepler Space Telescope?',
    options: [
      'It discovered the first exoplanet',
      'It confirmed the existence of dark matter',
      'It helped find thousands of exoplanets',
      'It was the first telescope in space'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'It helped find thousands of exoplanets',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which type of exoplanet is K2-18b?',
    options: ['Terrestrial', 'Super-Earth', 'Gas Giant', 'Ice Giant'],
    correctAnswer: 'Super-Earth',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What can scientists learn from studying exoplanet atmospheres?',
    options: [
      'Composition of the planet',
      'Presence of life',
      'Temperature',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which element is a key indicator of life in exoplanet atmospheres?',
    options: ['Carbon Dioxide', 'Oxygen', 'Nitrogen', 'Helium'],
    correctAnswer: 'Oxygen',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "transit" mean in exoplanet studies?',
    options: [
      'The passage of a planet in front of a star',
      'A star exploding',
      'A planet changing its orbit',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The passage of a planet in front of a star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What kind of planet is HD 209458 b known as?',
    options: ['Gas Giant', 'Super-Earth', 'Hot Jupiter', 'Ice Giant'],
    correctAnswer: 'Hot Jupiter',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which planet is often referred to as a "diamond planet"?',
    options: ['55 Cancri e', 'HD 189733 b', 'WASP-12b', 'TrES-2b'],
    correctAnswer: '55 Cancri e',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which characteristic is essential for a planet to be habitable?',
    options: ['Liquid water', 'High gravity', 'Large size', 'Close to the sun'],
    correctAnswer: 'Liquid water',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is the main goal of the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS)?',
    options: [
      'To search for asteroids',
      'To find exoplanets around bright stars',
      'To map the universe',
      'To observe black holes'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To find exoplanets around bright stars',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is a rogue planet?',
    options: [
      'A planet with an unstable orbit',
      'A planet that does not orbit a star',
      'A planet that orbits multiple stars',
      'A planet that has been ejected from its system'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A planet that does not orbit a star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which of the following exoplanets has been found to have water vapor in its atmosphere?',
    options: ['K2-18b', 'TRAPPIST-1d', 'WASP-121b', 'HD 209458 b'],
    correctAnswer: 'K2-18b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "light-year" measure?',
    options: ['Time', 'Distance', 'Mass', 'Temperature'],
    correctAnswer: 'Distance',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which star system has multiple Earth-sized exoplanets?',
    options: ['Alpha Centauri', 'TRAPPIST-1', 'Proxima Centauri', 'Betelgeuse'],
    correctAnswer: 'TRAPPIST-1',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What type of star is most likely to host exoplanets?',
    options: ['G-type stars', 'O-type stars', 'M-type stars', 'B-type stars'],
    correctAnswer: 'M-type stars',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the main component of the atmosphere of Venus?',
    options: ['Carbon Dioxide', 'Nitrogen', 'Oxygen', 'Hydrogen'],
    correctAnswer: 'Carbon Dioxide',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is an exoplanet candidate?',
    options: [
      'A confirmed exoplanet',
      'A potential exoplanet awaiting confirmation',
      'A planet in our solar system',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A potential exoplanet awaiting confirmation',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does "Radial Velocity" measure?',
    options: [
      'Distance to a planet',
      'Speed of a planet',
      'Color of a star',
      'Mass of a planet'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Speed of a planet',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which of the following planets is known for its extreme winds?',
    options: ['Neptune', 'Mars', 'Jupiter', 'Earth'],
    correctAnswer: 'Neptune',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What type of exoplanet is WASP-43b?',
    options: ['Super-Earth', 'Gas Giant', 'Ice Giant', 'Terrestrial'],
    correctAnswer: 'Gas Giant',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the temperature range for the planet HD 189733b?',
    options: ['-50 to 0°C', '0 to 1000°C', '500 to 1000°C', '1000 to 2000°C'],
    correctAnswer: '1000 to 2000°C',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which planet was the first to have its atmosphere analyzed?',
    options: ['WASP-121b', 'HD 209458b', '51 Pegasi b', 'TRAPPIST-1d'],
    correctAnswer: 'HD 209458b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which of these is an Earth-like exoplanet?',
    options: ['Kepler-186f', 'WASP-17b', 'GJ 357 d', 'K2-18b'],
    correctAnswer: 'Kepler-186f',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the purpose of the James Webb Space Telescope?',
    options: [
      'To study black holes',
      'To observe the early universe',
      'To find exoplanets',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which planet is known for its "hot Jupiter" status?',
    options: ['WASP-43b', 'K2-18b', 'Proxima Centauri b', 'Gliese 581d'],
    correctAnswer: 'WASP-43b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What do astronomers hope to find in the atmosphere of exoplanets?',
    options: ['Moons', 'Dust', 'Gases indicative of life', 'Stars'],
    correctAnswer: 'Gases indicative of life',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is the estimated number of exoplanets in the Milky Way?',
    options: ['10 million', '100 million', '1 billion', '100 billion'],
    correctAnswer: '100 billion',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What characteristic is often used to define a habitable zone?',
    options: [
      'Distance from the star',
      'Size of the planet',
      'Temperature of the star',
      'Composition of the planet'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Distance from the star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which gas is often considered a biosignature in exoplanet atmospheres?',
    options: ['Methane', 'Argon', 'Krypton', 'Xenon'],
    correctAnswer: 'Methane',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is the function of a spectrometer in exoplanet studies?',
    options: [
      'To measure distances',
      'To analyze light from planets',
      'To photograph stars',
      'To detect gravity waves'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To analyze light from planets',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which type of celestial object is a "brown dwarf"?',
    options: [
      'A planet',
      'A star',
      'An object between a star and a planet',
      'An asteroid'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'An object between a star and a planet',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "exoplanet" specifically refer to?',
    options: [
      'A planet in the solar system',
      'A planet orbiting another star',
      'A moon of another planet',
      'An asteroid'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A planet orbiting another star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the main goal of exoplanet research?',
    options: [
      'To find new stars',
      'To understand planetary systems',
      'To find extraterrestrial life',
      'To study black holes'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To find extraterrestrial life',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the "Transit Method" of detecting exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Measuring star brightness changes',
      'Detecting star motion',
      'Observing star color',
      'Analyzing gravitational waves'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Measuring star brightness changes',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is the average distance to the nearest star system, Alpha Centauri?',
    options: [
      '4.24 light-years',
      '2.5 light-years',
      '1.3 light-years',
      '10 light-years'
    ],
    correctAnswer: '4.24 light-years',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which exoplanet was the first to have its atmosphere detected?',
    options: ['HD 209458b', 'WASP-121b', '51 Pegasi b', 'TrES-2b'],
    correctAnswer: 'HD 209458b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "exoplanet migration" refer to?',
    options: [
      'Planets moving to a different star',
      'Planets changing their orbits',
      'The movement of planets during formation',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The movement of planets during formation',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the habitable zone around a star also known as?',
    options: ['Goldilocks Zone', 'Death Zone', 'Danger Zone', 'Sweet Spot'],
    correctAnswer: 'Goldilocks Zone',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is an ultra-hot Jupiter?',
    options: [
      'A small rocky planet',
      'A gas giant with high temperatures',
      'A planet similar to Earth',
      'A type of brown dwarf'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A gas giant with high temperatures',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What role does the planet\'s mass play in its ability to retain an atmosphere?',
    options: [
      'Larger mass means better retention',
      'Smaller mass means better retention',
      'Mass has no effect',
      'All planets retain atmospheres equally'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Larger mass means better retention',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which planet is known for its "ocean world" status?',
    options: ['Europa', 'Enceladus', 'Ganymede', 'All of the above'],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What type of planetary system is known as a "multi-planet system"?',
    options: [
      'A system with two or more planets',
      'A binary star system',
      'A star with one planet',
      'A rogue planet system'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A system with two or more planets',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which of these planets is considered a "mini-Neptune"?',
    options: ['GJ 1214 b', 'Kepler-186f', 'WASP-69b', 'K2-18b'],
    correctAnswer: 'GJ 1214 b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the significance of the K2 mission?',
    options: [
      'To study black holes',
      'To find exoplanets in different fields',
      'To observe supernovae',
      'To map the Milky Way'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To find exoplanets in different fields',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which technique uses the gravitational influence of a planet on its host star to detect exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Direct Imaging',
      'Radial Velocity',
      'Astrometry',
      'Transit Method'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Radial Velocity',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is the expected lifespan of the James Webb Space Telescope?',
    options: ['5 years', '10 years', '20 years', '30 years'],
    correctAnswer: '10 years',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the primary focus of the CHEOPS mission?',
    options: [
      'To study black holes',
      'To measure the sizes of exoplanets',
      'To observe supernovae',
      'To map the Milky Way'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'To measure the sizes of exoplanets',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'Which is the hottest exoplanet discovered so far?',
    options: ['WASP-121b', 'KELT-9b', 'HD 189733b', 'WASP-43b'],
    correctAnswer: 'KELT-9b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is an exomoon?',
    options: [
      'A moon orbiting a planet in our solar system',
      'A moon orbiting an exoplanet',
      'A planet with no moons',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A moon orbiting an exoplanet',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which of the following factors is crucial for the existence of life?',
    options: ['Temperature', 'Water', 'Atmosphere', 'All of the above'],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the significance of the TRAPPIST-1 system?',
    options: [
      'It has multiple Earth-sized exoplanets',
      'It is the closest star system',
      'It has a gas giant',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'It has multiple Earth-sized exoplanets',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'What is a potential biosignature in the atmosphere of an exoplanet?',
    options: ['Methane', 'Oxygen', 'Carbon Dioxide', 'All of the above'],
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which planet is known for having a thick atmosphere with high pressure?',
    options: ['Venus', 'Mars', 'Earth', 'Titan'],
    correctAnswer: 'Venus',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the main feature of a "Hot Jupiter"?',
    options: [
      'Close orbit to its star',
      'Cold temperatures',
      'Large size',
      'High density'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Close orbit to its star',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which of the following is a method of direct imaging of exoplanets?',
    options: [
      'Blocking starlight with a coronagraph',
      'Measuring star brightness',
      'Detecting Doppler shifts',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Blocking starlight with a coronagraph',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText:
        'Which is the first exoplanet discovered around a sun-like star?',
    options: ['51 Pegasi b', 'HD 209458b', 'Gliese 581g', 'Kepler-186f'],
    correctAnswer: '51 Pegasi b',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is the concept of "planetary habitability"?',
    options: [
      'The ability of a planet to support life',
      'The size of a planet',
      'The distance from a star',
      'The atmosphere of a planet'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The ability of a planet to support life',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What is a "super-Earth"?',
    options: [
      'A planet larger than Earth',
      'A planet smaller than Earth',
      'A moon of Earth',
      'A planet with no atmosphere'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A planet larger than Earth',
  ),
  Question(
    questionText: 'What does the term "goldilocks zone" refer to?',
    options: [
      'The habitable zone around a star',
      'A type of star',
      'A gas giant',
      'A black hole'
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The habitable zone around a star',
  )
];
